Software Engineer

Erik Skoog

www.skoog.codes

Summary

A Software Engineer with 4 years of experience in object-oriented programming, development, testing, debugging, and product/development management. Motivated to grow and diversify through experience as a Software Engineer. Experience managing a 5-member team and coordinating with business stakeholders to successfully software to discover business insights.

Experience

August 2021 - Current

Development Manager *UNL Raikes Design Studio*

Technologies: .NET, Neo4j, Azure Devops

- Develop a scalable, automated process for uploading data to a remote Neo4j server
- Implement dynamic, asynchronous functions for creating relationships and insights within Neo4j
- Implement a pipeline with automated testing to be run on a nightly basis
- Manage squad commitments for each sprint through user stories and Git VCS

June 2021 - Current

Software Engineer Intern *Medical Solutions*

Technologies: React, TypeScript, Node

- Develop architecture and solution for a Timesheet service to reach 1,000+ users
- Create testing strategies for new and existing services
- Create/maintain reusable software components within the Medical Solutions domain
- Engineer architecture for new services by identifying vulnerabilities in performance, readability, and maintainability

June 2020 - August 2020

Software Engineer Intern *Spreetail*

Technologies: .NET, React

- Contributing member of the Supply Chain Viper squad
- Built web-based software with .NET, SQL Server, and JavaScript to solve business problems faced by the Spreetail team and associated fulfillment centers
- Engineered in an Agile environment

Education

August 2018 - May 2022

Software Engineering

University of Nebraska-Lincoln

(Minors: Mathematics, Music Technology)

Skills

- Software Engineering
- Project Management
- Build Releases
- Code Reviews
- Writing/Communication
- Software Testing

Top Technologies

- React
- TypeScript
- .NET
- Python
- Git VCS

Contact

4416 Oakwood Lane West Des Moines, IA (515)-421-2171

euskoog@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.skoog.codes